<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Chemist Fun</string>
    <string name="really_long_string">Making elephant toothpaste is an easy and fun science experiment that you can do with your kids at home or with students in the lab. It is the result of a chemical reaction that creates a large amount of oozing foam. The movement of the foam looks like toothpaste squirting out of a tube while the amount of foam usually is enough for an elephant to brush its teeth.

    Please be aware the concentrated hydrogen peroxide (greater than the household 3%) is a strong oxidizer. It may bleach skin and could possibly cause burns. Do not attempt without proper safety precautions and the presence of an adult. Have fun with it, but be safe!</string>
    <string name="really_long_string1">The fungi in the yeast immediately cause the hydrogen peroxide to decompose and strip off an extra oxygen molecule. The yeast acts as a catalyst as it causes the hydrogen peroxide molecule to release an oxygen molecule. The stripped off oxygen molecule takes the form of a gas and once it hits the soap it creates fluffy foam bubbles, while the rest stays as water. The gas looks for an escape route and the foam “toothpaste” gushes out of the bottle.The chemical reaction is known as an exothermic reaction so heat is given off. The heat is not enough to cause any harm so you can definitely feel the foam and play around. The foam is just water, soap and oxygen so it isn’t toxic.</string>
    <string name="really_long_string2">As you lower the glass over the candle, the flame heats the air inside the glass.The glass contacts the surface of the water, trapping a volume of warm air.The candle goes out and this warm air cools rapidly.Air that cools rapidly under a constant pressure does so according to Charless law, a specific version of the ideal gas law that holds the quantity of gas and the pressure constant. Charless law holds that the ratio of Volume to Temperature is constant.Since the temperature decreases, the volume must also decrease.Additionally, some water vapor may condense on the sides of the glass and back into the liquid water. This also reduces the total volume of gas inside the glass.</string>

    <string name="really_long_string3">In this science experiment we will solve the mystery of why the water rises. You are going to
    have to keep your eyes glued to the experiment and observe  closely to figure it out. We will learn
    about air pressure in the process. Lets try the Why Does The Water Rise Experiment.</string>
    <string name="really_long_string4">This experiment will show you how to make sodium acetate (also known as sodium ethanoate), the sodium salt of acetic acid, using no lab equipment whatsoever. Sodium acetate can be used in the "hot ice" reaction and can also be made into a hot pack or cold pack.</string>
    <string name="really_long_string5">Chemical Reaction:NaHCO3 + CH3COOH ---> CH3COONa + CO2 + H2O </string>
    <string name="really_long_string6">Lemon juice is an organic substance that oxidizes and turns brown when heated. Diluting the lemon juice in water makes it very hard to notice when you apply it the paper, no one will be aware of its presence until it is heated and the secret message is revealed. Other substances which work in the same way include orange juice, honey, milk, onion juice, vinegar and wine. Invisible ink can also be made using chemical reactions or by viewing certain liquids under ultraviolet (UV) light.</string>
    <string name="really_long_string7">Making invisible ink is a lot of fun, you can pretend you are a secret agent as you keep all your secret codes and messages hidden from others. All you need is some basic household objects and the hidden power of lemon juice.</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
</resources>
